All right, everyone! This... is a stick-up!
Semua perhatian! Ini perampokan!
Don't anybody move!
Jangan ada yang bergerak!
Now, empty that safe!
Kosongkan lemari besi itu.
Money, money, money!
Uang, uang, uang.
Stop it! Stop it, you mean, old potato!
Hentikan, kentang tua jahat!
Quiet, Bo Peep, or your sheep get run over!
Diam, Bo Peep atau biri-birimu kubunuh.
Help! Baa! Help us!
Tolong! Tolong kami!
Oh, no, not my sheep! Somebody do something!
Jangan biri-biri kami! Tolong!
Reach for the sky!
Angkat tangan!
Oh, no! Sheriff Woody!
Oh, tidak! Sheriff Woody!
I'm here to stop you, One-Eyed Bart.
Aku akan mencegah Bart si mata satu.
How'd you know it was me?
Dari mana kau tahu ini aku?
Are you gonna come quietly?
Kau ingin ikut dengan tenang?
You can't touch me, Sheriff!
Kau tak bisa sentuh aku, Sheriff.
l brought my attack dog with the built-in force field.
Aku bawa anjing penyerangku yang dilengkapi medan pelindung.
Well, l brought my dinosaur who eats force-field dogs.
Aku bawa dinosaurus yang memakan anjing bermedan pelindung.
Yipe, yipe, yipe, yipe! You're going to jail, Bart!
Hore, hore! Kau akan masuk penjara, Bart.
Say goodbye to the wife and Tater Tots.
Ucapkan selamat tinggal pada istri dan Tater Tots.
You saved the day again, Woody.
Kau jadi penyelamat lagi, Woody.
You're my favorite deputy.
Kau polisi favoritku.
You've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
Come on, let's wrangle up the cattle.
Ayo kita kumpulkan ternaknya.
When the road looks rough ahead
Saat perjalanan tampak sulit...
And you're miles and miles from your nice, warm bed
dan kau jauh sekali dari ranjangmu yang empuk dan hangat...
Round 'em up, cowboy!
Kumpulkan mereka, koboi.
Just remember what your old pal said
ingat saja perkataan sahabat lamamu.
Boy, you've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
Yee-haw!
Hore!
Yeah, you've got a friend in me
Ya, aku adalah temanmu.
Hey, cowboy!
Hei, koboi!
Some other folks might be a little bit smarter than 1am
Beberapa orang mungkin lebih pandai dari aku.
Big and stronger too
Lebih besar dan kuat juga.
Come on, Woody.
Ayo, Woody.
Maybe
Mungkin.
But none of them will ever love you the way I do
Tapi tidak ada yang menyayangimu seperti aku.
It's me and you, boy
Hanya kau dan aku.
And as the years go by
Bertahun-tahun berlalu...
Whoa! Whoa!
Hore! Hore!
Our friendship will never die
persahabatan kita takkan pudar.
You're gonna see It's our destiny
Kau akan lihat, itu adalah takdir kita.
You've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
All right!
Hebat!
Yeah, you've got a friend in me
Ya, aku adalah temanmu.
Score!
Gol!
- You got a friend in me - Wow! Cool!
Aku adalah temanmu.! Wah! Hebat!
- What do you think? - Oh, this looks great, Mom!
Bagaimana menurutmu?) Oh, ini bagus, ibu!
Okay, birthday boy...
Baiklah, yang berulang tahun.
We saw that at the store! l asked you for it!
Kita lihat itu di toko! Aku minta itu!
- [hope I have enough places. - Wow, look at that! That's so...
Kuharap cukup tempat.! Wah, lihat itu.
- One, two... Four. - Oh, my gosh, you got...
1, 2... 4 Astaga, kau dapat...
- Yeah, I think that's gonna be enough. - Could we leave this up 'til we move?
Kukira itu cukup. Boleh ditinggalkan sampai kita pindah?
- Well, sure! We can leave it up. - Yeah!
Tentu, kita bisa biarkan saja.!Ya!
Now go get Molly. Your friends are gonna be here any minute.
Sekarang ambil Molly. Temanmu sebentar lagi datang.
Yee...haw!
Hore!
Howdy, little lady.
Apa kabar, nona kecil?
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
Ada yang meracuni sumber air.
Come on, Molly.
Ayo, Molly.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
Oh, kau semakin berat saja.
See you later, Woody.
Sampai jumpa, Woody.
Pull my string! The birthday party's today?
Astaga! Pesta ulang tahun itu hari ini?
Okay, everybody, coast is clear!
Keadaan sudah aman, semuanya!
Ages 3 and up. It's on my box.
Usia 3 tahun keatas, tertulis di kotakku.
Ages 3 and up. I'm not supposed to be baby-sitting Princess Drool.
Usia 3 tahun keatas. Aku bukannya menjaga Putri Liur itu.
Hey, Hamm.
Hei, Hamm.
- Look, I'm Picasso! - [don't get it.
Lihat, aku Picasso!! Aku tak paham.
You uncultured swine! What're you lookin’ at, ya hockey puck?
Babi yang tak berbudaya. Lihat apa kau, bola hockey?
- Hey, Sarge, have you seen Slinky? - Sir! No, sir!
Sersan, kau lihat Slinky? Tidak, Pak!
Okay. Hey, thank you. At ease.
Terima kasih. Istirahat di tempat.
Hey, uh, Slinky?
Hei, Slinky?
Right here, Woody. I'm red this time.
Di sini, Woody. Kali ini aku merah.
- No. Slink... - Oh, well, all right.
Tidak. Slink...'Oh, baiklah.
You can be red if you want.
Kau boleh yang merah jika kau ingin.
- Not now, Slink. l got some bad news. - Bad news?
Jangan sekarang, Slink. Ada kabar buruk.!Kabar buruk?
Just gather everyone up for a staff meeting, and be happy.
Kumpulkan untuk pertemuan dan bergembiralah.
Got it.
Mengerti.
Be happy!
Bergembiralah.
Staff meeting, everybody! Snake, Robot, podium duty.
Pertemuan. Ular, Robot, tugas di podium.
Hey.
Hei.
Hey, Etch. Draw!
Hei, Etch. Gambar.
Oh! Got me again.
Oh! Aku kena lagi.
Etch, you've been working on that draw. Fastest knobs in the West.
Kau sudah berlatih menarik pistolmu. Tombol tercepat di Barat.
Got a staff meeting, you guys. Come on, let's go.
Ada pertemuan. Ayo, cepat.
Now, where is that... Oh.
Dimana?
Hey, who moved my doodle pad way over here?
Siapa yang memindahkan papan gambar kemari?
- How're you doin’, Rex? - Were you scared? Tell me honestly.
Apa kabar, Rex?) Kau takut? Katakan sejujurnya.
Il was close to being scared that time.
Waktu itu aku nyaris takut.
I'm going for fearsome here, but I just don't feel it.
Aku akan menakutkan tapi aku tak merasakannya.
I think I'm just coming off as annoying.
Kukira aku hanya akan menyebalkan saja.
Oh, hi, Bo. Hi.
Oh, hai, Bo. Hai.
l wanted to thank you, Woody, for saving my flock.
Terima kasih, Woody, kau telah menyelamatkan ternakku.
Oh, hey, it was, uh, nothin’.
Oh, hei, itu bukan apa-apa.
What do you say I get someone else to watch the sheep tonight?
Bagaimana jika aku minta orang lain menjaga ternakku malam ini?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, ya!
Remember, I'm just a couple of blocks away.
Ingat, tempatku hanya beberapa blok saja jauhnya.
- Yodel-ay-hee-hoo! - Come on, come on.
Yodel-ay-hee-hoo!)Ayo, ayo.
Smaller toys up front.
Mainan kecil di depan.
Hey, Woody, come on.
Hei, Woody, ayo.
Oh, thanks, Mike.
Oh, terima kasih, Mike.
Okay... Whoa, whoa. Step back.
Baiklah. Tahan. Mundur.
- For crying out loud. - Thank you.
Astaga.fTerima kasih.
Hello? Check. That better? Great.
Halo? Periksa. Lebih baik? Bagus.
Everybody hear me? Up on the shelf, can you hear me? Great.
Semuanya bisa dengar aku? Yang di rak bisa dengar suaraku? Bagus.
Okay. First item today:
Hal pertama hari ini.
Oh, yeah. Has everyone picked a moving buddy?
Oh, ya. Semuanya sudah memilih teman untuk pindah?
- What? - Moving buddy? You can't be serious.
Apa?Teman pindah? la pasti bergurau.
I didn't know we were supposed to have one already.
Aku tak tahu harus punya teman.
Do we have to hold hands?
Kita harus bergandeng tangan?
You guys think this is a big joke.
Kalian pikir ini hanya lelucon.
We've only got one week left before the move.
Satu minggu lagi kita pindah.
I don't want any toys left behind. A moving buddy.
Aku tak mau ada mainan yang tertinggal. Teman pindah.
If you don't have one, get one!
Kalau belum punya teman, carilah!
All right, next. Oh, yes.
Baik, selanjutnya. Oh, ya.
Tuesday night's plastic corrosion awareness meeting
Rapat kesadaran korosi plastik selasa malam...
was, I think, a big success.
kurasa berhasil dengan baik.
And we wanna thank Mr. Spell for putting that on for us.
Kita mau berterima kasih pada Tn. Spell yang membantu kita.
- Thank you, Mr. Spell. - You're welcome.
Terima kasih, Tn. Spell.' Kembali.
Okay. Oh, yes. One minor note here.
Baiklah. Oh, ya. Satu catatan kecil.
Andy's birthday party has been moved to today.
Pesta ulang tahun Andy diubah menjadi hari ini.
Wait a minute here!
Tunggu sebentar.
What do you mean the party's today? His birthday's not ‘til next week!
Apa maksudmu? Ulang tahunnya minggu depan.
What's goin’ on down there? Is his mom losin’ her marbles?
Ada apa? Ibunya sudah lupa?
Well, obviously she wanted to have the party before the move.
Sudah jelas ibunya ingin mengadakan pesta sebelum pindah.
I'm not worried. You shouldn't be worried.
Aku tak cemas. Kalian tak usah cemas.
Of course Woody ain't worried. He's been Andy's favorite since kindergarten.
Tentu saja Woody tidak khawatir. la mainan kesukaan Andy sejak TK.
Hey, hey. Come on, Potato Head.
Hei, hei. Sudahlah, Potato Head.
If Woody says it's all right, then, well, darn it, it's good enough for me.
Kalau Woody bilang tak apa-apa, aku percaya saja.
Woody has never steered us wrong before.
Woody tidak pernah menyesatkan kita.
Come on, guys. Every Christmas and birthday we go through this.
Sudahlah. Kita mengalami hal ini tiap Natal dan ulang tahun.
But what if Andy gets another dinosaur, a mean one?
Bagaimana jika Andy dapat dinosaurus lainnya? Yang galak?
I just don't think I could take that kind of rejection!
Rasanya aku tidak tahan jika dicampakkan!
Hey, listen, no one's getting replaced.
Dengar, takkan ada yang diganti.
This is Andy we're talking about.
Yang kita bicarakan ini Andy.
It doesn't matter how much we're played with.
Tak masalah berapa sering kita dimainkan.
What matters is that we're here for Andy when he needs us.
Yang penting kita siap untuk Andy jika ia membutuhkan kita.
That's what we're made for, right?
Kita dibuat untuk itu, bukan?
Pardon me. I hate to break up the staff meeting, but... they're here!
Maaf. Aku tak suka mengganggu rapat ini tapi mereka sudah tiba.
Birthday guests at three o'clock!
Tamu ulang tahun di arah pukul 3!
Stay calm, everyone!
Semua tenang.
Hey!
Hei!
Meeting adjourned.
Pertemuan ditunda.
Ho, boy! Will you take a look at all those presents?
Astaga! Coba lihat hadiah-hadiah itu.
I can't see a thing.
Aku tidak bisa melihat.
Yes, sir, we're next month's garage sale fodder for sure.
Bulan depan kita pasti akan dijual obral.
- Any dinosaur-shaped ones? - Oh, for crying out loud.
Ada mainan dinosaurus?) Oh, yang benar saja.
- They're all in boxes, you idiot. - They're getting bigger.
Hadiah itu masih di dalam kotak.! Hadiah itu semakin besar.
Wait, there's a nice little one over there.
Tunggu, ada hadiah kecil bagus.
Hi!
Hai!
- Spell: trash can. - We're doomed!
Eja: sampah.Tamatlah kita.
All right! All right!
Baiklah!
If l send out the troops, will you all calm down?
Jika aku kirim pasukan, kalian akan tenang?
- Yes! Yes! We promise! - Okay! Save your batteries.
Ya! Kami janji.! Baiklah! Hemat baterai kalian.
Very good, Woody. That's using the old noodle.
Bagus sekali, Woody. Kau memakai otak.
Sergeant, establish a recon post downstairs. Code Red!
Sersan, dirikan pos pengawasan di bawah. Siaga merah.
- You know what to do. - Yes, sir!
Kau tahu tugasmu.Ya, Pak!
All right, men. You heard him. Code Red!
Kalian sudah dengar. Siaga merah.
Repeat, we are at Code Red. Recon plan Charlie. Execute!
Kita dalam siaga merah. Rencana pengintaian Charlie. Laksanakan!
Let's move! Move, move, move, move!
Ayo! Cepat!
Yeah!
Hore!
Okay, come on, kids.
Ayo, anak-anak!
Everyone in the living room. It's almost time for the presents.
Semuanya ke ruang keluarga. Waktunya untuk membuka hadiah.
All right, gangway, gangway.
Minggir, minggir.
And this is how we find out
Inilah cara kita mengetahui...
what is in those presents.
isi hadiah-hadiah itu.
Okay, who's hungry?
Siapa yang lapar?
Here come the chips!
Ini keripiknya.
I've got Cool Ranch and barbecue!
Ada keripik rasa Cool Ranch dan keripik bakar.
What in the world... Oh!
Ada apa? Oh!
I thought I told him to pick these up.
Aku sudah menyuruh Andy untuk menyimpan mainan ini.
Shouldn't they be there by now? What's taking them so long?
Mereka harusnya sudah tiba, bukan? Mengapa lama sekali?
Hey, these guys are professionals. They're the best.
Mereka profesional. Mereka yang terbaik.
Come on! They're not lying down on the job.
Ayolah. Mereka tak menunda pekerjaan.
Go on without me! Just go!
Tinggalkan saja aku. Pergilah.
A good soldier never leaves a man behind.
Prajurit yang baik tak pernah meninggalkan teman.
Okay, everybody, come on.
Baiklah, semuanya, ayo.
Everybody settle down. Now, kids. Everybody...
Semuanya harus tenang. Anak-anak. Semuanya...
You sit in a circle. No, Andy. Andy, you sit in the middle there.
Kalian duduk buat lingkaran. Andy, kau duduk di tengah.
Good. And... Which present are you gonna open first?
Bagus. Kau ingin buka hadiah mana dulu?
- Mine! - There they are.
Dari aku.! Itu dia hadiahnya.
Come in, Mother Bird. This is Alpha Bravo.
Masuk, Mother Bird. Ini Alpha Bravo.
- This is it! This is it! Quiet, quiet! - Come in, Mother Bird.
Ini dia! Diam!! Masuk, Mother Bird.
Alf right, Andy's opening the first present now.
Andy membuka hadiah pertamanya sekarang.
Mrs. Potato Head! Mrs. Potato Head! Mrs. Potato Head!
Ny. Potato Head! Ny. Potato Head! Ny. Potato Head!
Hey, I can dream, can't I?
Aku boleh bermimpi, bukan?
The bow's coming off. He's ripping the wrapping paper.
Pitanya dilepas. la merobek bungkusnya.
It's a... It's... It's a... a lunch box.
Itu, itu, itu kotak makan siang.
- We've got a lunch box here. - Alunch box?
Itu kotak makan siang. Kotak makan siang?
- Lunch box? - For lunch.
Kotak makan siang?! Untuk makan siang.
Okay, second present. It appears to be...
Hadiah kedua. Tampaknya itu...
- Okay, it's bed sheets. - Who invited that kid?
Bagus. Itu seprai. Siapa yang mengundang anak itu?
Oh! Only one left.
Oh! Hanya tinggal satu!
- Okay, we're on the last present now. - Last present!
Sekarang hadiah terakhir. Hadiah terakhir.
It's a big one. It's a...
Hadiahnya besar. Itu...
- It's a board game! Repeat, Battleship! - Whew!
Itu papan permainan! Ulangi: kapal perang!
Hallelujah!
Aleluya!
- Yeah! All right! - Hey, watch it!
Hati-hati.Maaf.
Sorry there, old spud head.
Maaf, kepala kentang.
Mission accomplished. Well done, men. Pack it up. We're goin' home.
Tugas selesai. Bagus. Selesai. Kita pulang.
So did I tell ya? Nothin’ to worry about.
Aku bilang apa? Tidak perlu khawatir.
I knew you were right all along, Woody. Never doubted ya for a second.
Aku tahu kau benar, Woody. Aku tak pernah meragukanmu.
Wait a minute. Oh!
Tunggu. Oh!
- What do we have here? - Wait! Turn that thing back on!
Ada apa di sini?! Hidupkan kembali radio itu!
Come in, Mother Bird!
Masuk, Mother Bird!
Andy's opening it. He's really excited about this one.
Andy sedang membukanya. la tampak senang sekali.
- Mom, what is it? - It's a huge package.
Ibu, apa itu?! Hadiahnya besar sekali.
Oh, get outta the... One of the kids is in the way. I can't see.
Oh, minggir. Satu anak menutupi. Aku tak bisa melihat.
-It'sa... - Wow!
Itu...AVah!
It's a what? What is it?
Itu apa? Hadiahnya apa?
- Oh, no! - Oh, ya big lizard!
Oh, tidak!Kadal besar.
- Now we'll never know what it is! - Way to go, Rex!
kita kini takkan tahu apa isinya.! Bagus, Rex.
No, no! Turn him around! Turn him around!
Tidak! Balikkan dia!
He's puttin’ 'em in backwa... Here, you're puttin’ 'em in backwards!
la menaruhnya terbalik. Ini, kau menaruhnya terbalik.
Plus is positive, minus is negative! Oh, let me!
Plus itu positif. Minus itu negatif. Biar aku saja.
Let's go to my room, guys!
Ayo ke kamarku.
Red alert! Red alert! Andy is coming upstairs!
Bahaya, bahaya. Andy ke atas.
- There! - Juvenile intrusion!
Begitulah!) Serangan anak-anak!
Repeat, resume your positions now!
Ulangi, kembali ke posisi kalian!
Andy's coming! Everybody, back to your places! Hurry!
Andy datang! Semua kembali ke tempatnya! Cepat!
Get to your places!
Kembali ke tempatmu!
Out of my way! Here I come! Here I come!
Minggir! Aku datang! Aku datang!
Hey, look, its lasers light up. Take that, Zurg!
Lihat, lasernya menyala. Rasakan ini, Zurg!
Quick, make a space. This is where the spaceship lands.
Cepat! Beri tempat. Ini pesawat ruang angkasa mendarat.
And he does it like that. And he does a karate chop action!
la melakukannya seperti ini. la melakukan gerakan karate.
Come on down, guys! It's time for games!
Ayo turun! Saatnya untuk bermain!
- What the heck is up there? - Woody, who's up there with ya?
Apa itu di atas?) Woody, siapa yang bersamamu?
Woody?
Woody?
- What are you doing under the bed? - Nothin’. Nothin’.
Woody, mengapa kau di bawah tempat tidur?Tidak ada apa-apa.
I'm sure Andy was just a little excited, that's all.
Kukira Andy terlalu bersemangat, itu saja.
Well, that mistake is sitting in your spot, Woody.
Kekeliruan itu berada di tempatmu, Woody.
- Have you been replaced? - What did I tell you earlier?
Kau telah digantikan? Aku tadi bilang apa?
No one is getting replaced.
Tidak ada yang diganti.
Now, let's all be polite and give whatever it is up there
Mari kita bersikap sopan dan berikan apapun yang ada di atas sana...
a nice, big Andy's-room welcome.
sambutan hangat kamar Andy.
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
Buzz Lightyear memanggil Star Command.
Come in, Star Command.
Jawab, Star Command.
Star Command, come in. Do you read me?
Star Command, jawab. Dengar suaraku?
Why don't they answer? My ship!
Mengapa mereka tak menjawab? Kapalku!
Blast! This'll take weeks to repair.
Sial! Untuk memperbaikinya butuh waktu berminggu-minggu.
Buzz Lightyear mission log, stardate 4-0-7-2.
Catatan misi Buzz Lightyear, 4072 waktu bintang.
My ship has run off course en route to sector 12.
Pesawatku keluar dari jalur saat menuju Sektor 12.
I've crash-landed on a strange planet.
Aku mendarat darurat di planet aneh.
The impact must've awoken me from hypersleep.
Benturan itu pasti telah membangunkanku dari tidur.
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
Datarannya tampak agak tak stabil.
No readout yet if the air is breathable.
GAMMA SEKTOR 4
And there seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
Tampaknya tak ada tanda-tanda makhluk berakal.
Hello!
Halo!
Whoa! Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Tahan! Hei! Tunggu, tunggu, tunggu!
Did I frighten you? Didn't mean to.
Aku mengejutkanmu? Aku tak bermaksud begitu.
Sorry. Howdy. My name is Woody.
Maaf. Halo. Namaku Woody.
And this is Andy's room. That's all l wanted to say.
Ini kamar Andy. Aku hanya ingin mengatakan itu.
And also, there has been a bit of a mix-up.
Juga ada sedikit kesalahan.
This is my spot, see, the bed here.
Ini tempatku. Tempat tidur ini.
Local law enforcement. It's about time you got here.
Penegak hukum. Sudah saatnya kau tiba.
My ship has crash-landed here by mistake.
Pesawatku mendarat darurat disini.
Yes, it is a mistake because, you see, the bed here is my spot.
Ya, ini kesalahan karena tempat tidur ini adalah tempatku.
I need to repair my turbo boosters.
Aku harus perbaiki penguat turboku.
Do you people still use fossil fuel, or have you discovered crystallic fusion?
Kalian masih pakai BBM atau sudah temukan perpaduan kristal?
Well, let's see. We got double-A's.
Coba aku lihat. Baterainya dua.
Watch yourself! Halt! Who goes there?
Hati-hati! Tunggu! Siapa itu?
Don't shoot! It's okay. Friends.
Jangan tembak! Ini teman.
- Do you know these life-forms? - Yes! They're Andy's toys.
Kau mengenal mereka?) Ya. Mereka mainan Andy.
All right, everyone, you're clear to come up.
Baiklah. Kalian boleh naik.
lam Buzz Lightyear. Il come in peace.
Aku Buzz Lightyear. Aku tak bermaksud jahat.
Oh, I'm so glad you're not a dinosaur!
Aku senang kau bukan dinosaurus.
Wh-why, thank you!
Sampai jumpa. Terima kasih.
Now, thank you all for your kind welcome!
Terima kasih atas sambutan kalian yang baik.
- Say, what's that button do? - I'll show you.
Tombol itu untuk apa?! Akan aku tunjukkan.
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
Buzz Lightyear menyelamatkan!
Hey, Woody's got something like that. His is a pull string.
Woody bisa bicara juga. Talinya bisa ditarik.
- Only it's... - Only it sounds like a car ran over it.
Hanya itu..!Hanya saja suaranya seperti dilindas mobil.
Oh, yeah, but not like this. This is a quality sound system.
Oh, ya, Tapi tak seperti ini. Ini sistem suara yang bagus.
Probably all copper wiring, huh?
Mungkin pakai kabel tembaga.
So, where you from? Singapore? Hong Kong?
Kau dari mana? Singapura? Hong Kong?
Well, no. Actually, I'm stationed up in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector Four.
Bukan. Sebenarnya aku ditugaskan di kuadran Gamma sektor 4.
As a member of the elite Universe Protection Unit
Sebagai anggota Unit elit Perlindungan Alam Semesta...
of the Space Ranger Corps,
Korps Penjaga Angkasa...
I protect the galaxy from the threat of invasion
AKU MELINDUNGI GALAKSI DARI ANCAMAN SERANGAN KAISAR KEJAM ZURG, MUSUH BEBUYUTAN ALIANSI GALAKSI. Aku melindungi galaksi dari ancaman serangan...
from the evil Emperor Zurg, sworn enemy of the Galactic Alliance.
AKU MELINDUNGI GALAKSI DARI ANCAMAN SERANGAN KAISAR KEJAM ZURG, MUSUH BEBUYUTAN ALIANSI GALAKSI. Kaisar kejam Zurg...
Oh, really? I'm from Playskool.
Oh, begitukah? Aku dari Playskool.
And I'm from Mattel. Well, I'm not really from Mattel.
Aku dari Mattel. Aku sebenarnya bukan dari Mattel.
I'm actually from a smaller company that was purchased in a leveraged buyout.
Sebenarnya dari perusahaan kecil yang dibeli.
You'd think they'd never seen a new toy before.
Mereka memang belum pernah melihat mainan baru.
Well, sure. Look at him. He's got more gadgets on him than a Swiss Army knife.
Coba lihat dia. Peralatannya banyak sekali.
Please be careful.
Hati-hati.
You don't want to be in the way when my laser goes off.
Jangan sampai tertembak laserku.Sinar laser!
Hey, a laser! How come you don't have a laser, Woody?
Mengapa kau tak punya laser, Woody?
It's not a laser! It's a... It's a little light bulb that blinks.
Itu bukan laser. Itu lampu kecil yang menyala.
- What's with him? - Laser envy.
Dia kenapa7'Iri pada laser.
All right, that's enough!
Cukup.
Look, we're all very impressed with Andy's new toy.
Kita semua kagum pada mainan baru Andy.
- Toy? - T-O-Y. Toy!
Mainan?! M-A-I-N-A-N. Mainan.
Excuse me, I think the word you're searching for is "Space Ranger."
Maaf, mungkin yang kau maksud Penjaga Angkasa.
The word I'm searching for I can't say because there's preschool toys present.
Kata yang aku cari tak bisa diucapkan sebab ada mainan untuk anak balita.
Gettin’ kinda tense, aren't ya?
Kau sedikit tegang, bukan?
Mr. Lightyear, now, I'm curious.
Tn. Lightyear, aku ingin tahu.
What does a Space Ranger actually do?
Apa tugas Penjaga Angkasa?
He's not a Space Ranger!
Dia bukan Penjaga Angkasa.
He doesn't fight evil or, or shoot lasers or fly!
la tak perangi penjahat, tembakkan laser atau terbang.
Excuse me.
Apa?
Oh, impressive wingspan! Very good!
Sayap yang hebat. Bagus!
Oh, what? What? These are plastic. He can't fly!
Oh, apa? Ini plastik. la tak bisa terbang.
They are a terillium-carbonic alloy, and I can fly.
Ini terbuat dari logam terilium karbon dan aku bisa terbang.
- No, you can't. - Yes, I can.
Tidak bisa.JBisa.
Can't. Can't. Can't!
Tidak bisa. Tidak bisa!
I tell you, I could fly around this room with my eyes closed!
Aku bisa terbang di ruangan ini dengan mata tertutup.
- Okay, then, Mr. Light Beer, prove it. - All right, then, I will.
Baiklah, Tn. Light Beer, buktikan.' Baiklah.
Stand back, everyone!
Semua menyingkir.
To infinity and beyond!
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
- Can! - Whoa!
Bisa!Wah!
Oh, wow, you flew magnificently!
Kau terbang dengan hebat!
- [found my movin' buddy. - Thank you. Thank you all. Thank you.
Aku dapat teman pindah.! Terima kasih semuanya.
That wasn't flying! That was... falling with style.
Itu bukan terbang. Itu jatuh dengan gaya.
Man, the dolls must really go for you. Can you teach me that?
Gadis-gadis pasti suka padamu. Kau bisa mengajari aku?
- Golly bob howdy! - Oh, shut up!
Astaga!!Oh, diam.
You know, in a couple of days,
Dalam beberapa hari...
everything will be just the way it was. They'll see.
semuanya akan seperti semula. Mereka akan lihat.
I'm still Andy's favorite toy.
Aku tetap mainan kesukaan Andy.
! was on top of the world livin’ high
Hidupku menyenangkan, serba mewah.
It was right in my pocket
Semuanya memuaskan.
! was livin’ the life
Aku hidup dengan gaya.
Things were just the way they should be
Semua seperti yang seharusnya.
When from out of the sky like a bomb
Lalu muncul mendadak seperti bom...
Comes some little punk in a rocket
datang orang brengsek dengan roket.
Now alf of a sudden some strange things are happening to me
Kini ada hal-hal aneh yang terjadi kepadaku.
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
Buzz Lightyear menyelamatkan!
Strange
Hal-hal...
Things are happening to me
aneh terjadi padaku.
Things
aneh.
Strange things are happening to me
Hal-hal aneh yang terjadi kepadaku.
Ain't no doubt about it
Tidak diragukan lagi.
! had friends ! had lots of friends
Dahulu aku punya banyak teman.
Now aif my friends are gone
Kini semua temanku pergi...
And I'm doin’ the best l can
dan aku berusaha sebaik-baiknya...
To carry on
untuk melanjutkan hidupku.
- l had power - Power
Aku punya kekuatan.Kekuatan.
- l was respected - Respected
Aku dihormati.JDihormati.
But not any more
Tapi tidak lagi...
And I've lost the love of the one
dan aku kehilangan cinta seseorang...
Whom I adore
yang aku kagumi.
Let me tell you ‘bout it Strange
Mari aku ceritakan. Hal-hal...
Things are happenin’ to me
aneh terjadi padaku.
Things
aneh.
Strange
Hal-hal...
Things are happenin’ to me
aneh terjadi padaku.
Ain't no doubt about it
Itu tidak diragukan.
Strange
Hal-hal...
Things
aneh.
Finally!
Akhirnya!
Hey, who's got my hat?
Siapa yang menyimpan topiku?
Look, I'm Woody! Howdy, howdy, howdy!
Lihat, aku Woody! Halo, halo, halo!
Gimme that!
Kembalikan.
Say there, Lizard and Stretchy Dog, let me show you something.
Kadang dan Anjing Mulur, aku akan menunjukkan sesuatu.
It looks as though I've been accepted into your culture.
Aku diterima di lingkunganmu.
Your chief, Andy, inscribed his name on me.
Pemimpinmu, Andy telah menuliskan namanya di sepatuku.
Wow!
Wah!
With permanent ink too!
Dengan tinta yang tak bisa dihapus.
Well, l must get back to repairing my ship.
Aku harus memperbaiki pesawatku.
Don't let it get to you, Woody.
Jangan sampai itu mempengaruhimu, Woody.
Let what? I don't... What do you mean? Who?
Membiarkan apa? Apa maksudmu? Siapa?
I know Andy's excited about Buzz.
Aku tahu Andy suka sekali pada Buzz.
But you know he'll always have a special place for you.
Tapi ia selalu punya tempat yang istimewa untukmu.
- Yeah, like the attic. - All right, that's it!
Ya, di gudang loteng.'Cukup.
Unidirectional bonding strip.
Pita pengikat segala arah.
Mr. Lightyear wants more tape.
Tn. Lightyear minta tambah perekat.
Listen, Light Snack, you stay away from Andy.
Dengar, Light Snack, jauhi Andy.
He's mine, and no one is taking him away from me.
Dia milikku. Tak ada yang boleh merebutnya dariku.
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Where's that bonding strip?
Mana pita perekat itu?
And another thing:
Satu hal lagi.
Stop with this spaceman thing! It's getting on my nerves!
Hentikan sikap manusia luar angkasamu. Itu menyebalkan.
Are you saying you wanna lodge a complaint with Star Command?
Kau ingin mengadu pada Komando Bintang?
Okay! Well, so you wanna do it the hard way, huh?
Baik. Kau mau dengan cara kekerasan?
- Don't even think about it, cowboy. - Oh, yeah, tough guy?
Jangan coba-coba, koboi.! Begitukah, jagoan?
The air isn't... toxic.
Udaranya tidak beracun.
How dare you open a spaceman's helmet on an uncharted planet!
Beraninya kau membuka helm astronot di planet asing.
My eyeballs could've been sucked from their sockets!
Bola mataku bisa tersedot keluar dari rongganya.
You actually think you're the Buzz Lightyear?
Kau benar-benar mengira bahwa kau Buzz Lightyear?
Oh, all this time I thought it was an act!
Oh, kukira itu hanya pura-pura.
Hey, guys, look! It's the real Buzz Lightyear!
Lihat, semuanya! Ini Buzz Lightyear sungguhan!
You're mocking me, aren't you?
Kau mengejek aku, bukan?
Oh, no, no. No, no, no, no, no. Buzz, look, an alien!
Oh, tidak. Buzz, lihat, makhluk asing.
Where?
Mana?
Yes!
Ya!
It's Sid!
Itu Sid!
Don't move!
Jangan bergerak.
I thought he was at summer camp.
Kukira ia sedang berkemah.
They must've kicked him out early this year.
Rupanya ia dipulangkan lebih cepat.
Oh, no, not Sid!
Oh, tidak, jangan Sid!
Incoming!
Awas!
- Who is it this time? - L... Lean't... can't tell.
Siapa korbannya kali ini?! Aku tak tahu.
- Hey, where's Lenny? - Right here, Woody.
Hei, Lenny mana?Disini, Woody.
Oh, no, I can't bear to watch one of these again.
Aku tak tega melihat hal itu lagi.
Oh, no, it's a Combat Carl.
Oh, tidak, itu Combat Carl.
What's going on?
Ada apa?
Nothing that concerns you spacemen, just us toys.
Bukan urusanmu astronot, hanya kami mainan saja.
I'd better take a look anyway.
Sebaiknya aku melihat.
Why is that soldier strapped to an explosive device?
Kenapa prajurit itu dipasangi bom?
That's why: Sid.
Karena itu Sid.
Sure is a hairy fellow.
Dia banyak bulunya.
No, no, that's Scud, you idiot.
Bukan. Itu Scud, bodoh.
That is Sid.
Itu Sid.
- You mean that happy child? - That ain't no happy child.
Anak yang gembira itu?! Itu bukan anak gembira.
He tortures toys, just for fun!
la gemar menyiksa mainan.
Well, then we've got to do something.
Kalau begitu kita harus bertindak.
What are you doing? Get down from there!
Apa yang kau lakukan? Jangan di situ.
- I'm gonna teach that boy a lesson. - Yeah, sure. You go ahead.
Aku akan memberinya pelajaran.! Ya, boleh. Silahkan.
Melt him with your scary laser.
Lelehkan dia dengan lasermu yang menyeramkan.
Be careful with that! It's extremely dangerous.
Hati-hati. Laser ini sangat berbahaya.
He's lighting it! He's lighting it! Hit the dirt!
la menyulut petasan. Tiarap!
Look out!
Awas!
Yes! He's gone! He's history!
Ya! Sudah tak ada. Dia sudah hancur!
I could've stopped him.
Aku harusnya bisa mencegahnya.
Buzz, I would love to see you try.
Buzz, aku ingin sekali melihatmu mencoba.
Of course, I'd love to see you as a crater.
Aku ingin sekali melihatmu jadi kawah.
The sooner we move, the better.
Lebih cepat kita pindah, lebih baik.
Yeah!
Ya!
To infinity and beyond!
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
All this packing makes me hungry.
Semua kemas-kemas ini membuat aku lapar.
What would you say to dinner at, oh, Pizza Planet?
Bagaimana jika kita makan malam di Pizza Planet?
Pizza Planet? Oh, cool!
Pizza Planet? Oh, bagus!
Go wash your hands, and I'll get Molly ready.
Cuci tangan dan ibu ambil Molly.
- Can I bring some toys? - You can bring one toy.
Boleh aku bawa mainan?) Hanya satu saja.
- Just one? - One toy?
Hanya satu?Satu mainan?
Will Andy pick me?
Andy akan memilihku?
"Don't count on it"?
“Jangan harap”?
Buzz! Oh, Buzz! Buzz Lightyear.
Buzz! Oh, Buzz! Buzz Lightyear.
Buzz Lightyear, thank goodness. We've got trouble!
Buzz Lightyear, syukurlah. Kami dapat masalah.
- Trouble? Where? - Down there. Just down there.
Masalah? Mana?) Dibawah. Dibawah sana.
A helpless toy, it's... it's trapped, Buzz!
Mainan tak berdaya. la terjebak, Buzz.
Then we've no time to lose.
Kita tak bisa buang-buang waktu.
I don't see anything!
Aku tak melihat apa-apa.
Oh, he's there! Just, just keep looking!
Oh, di disana. Tetaplah mencari.
What kind of toy...
Mainan macam apa...
Buzz!
Buzz!
I don't see him in the driveway.
Aku tak melihatnya.
- [ think he bounced into Sid's yard! - Oh! Buzz!
Kurasa ia terlempar ke halaman Sid.'Oh! Buzz!
Hey, everyone, R.C.'s trying to say something. What is it, boy?
Hei, semua, R.C. ingin mengatakan sesuatu. Ada apa, Nak?
- He's saying that this was no accident. - What do you mean?
Menurutnya itu bukan kecelakaan.! Apa maksudmu?
- [mean Humpty-Dumpty was pushed... - No!
Maksudku Humpty-Dumpty didorong...'Tidak.
.. by Woody!
oleh Woody!
- What? - Wait a minute.
Apa?!Tunggu.
You don't think I meant to knock Buzz out the window, do you? Potato Head?
Kau tak mengira aku menjatuhkan Buzz dari jendela, begitukah, Potato Head?
That's Mr. Potato Head to you, you back-stabbing murderer!
Panggil aku Tn. Potato Head, pembunuh!
Now, it was an accident, guys.
Itu tidak sengaja.
Come on. Now, you, you gotta believe me.
Kalian harus percaya padaku.
We believe ya, Woody. Right, Rex?
Kami percaya padamu, Woody. Benarkah, Rex?
Well, ye... N... I don't like confrontations!
Aku tak suka perselisihan.
Where is your honor, dirt bag? You are an absolute disgrace!
Mana kehormatanmu, penjahat? Kau memang memalukan!
You don't deserve to... Hey!
Kau tidak patut untuk... Hei!
You couldn't handle Buzz cutting in on your playtime, could you, Woody?
Kau tak suka karena kau disaingi oleh Buzz?
Didn't wanna face the fact that Buzz just might be Andy's new favorite toy.
Kau tak bisa menerima bahwa Buzz jadi mainan baru kesukaan Andy...
So you got rid of him.
jadi kau menyingkirkannya.
Well, what if Andy starts playing with me more, Woody, huh?
Bagaimana jika Anda mulai memainkan aku lagi?
You gonna knock me outta the window too?
Kau akan menjatuhkan aku dari jendela juga?
I don't think we should give him the chance.
Jangan sampai dia berbuat begitu.
There he is, men. Frag him!
Itu dia. Hajar dia!
Let's string him up by his pull string!
Ikat dia dengan tali suaranya!
- [got dibs on his hat! - Would you boys stop it!
Aku akan mendapatkan topinya.! Hentikan!
Tackle him!
Tangkap dia!
No, no, no! Wait! Il can explain everything!
Tunggu, aku bisa jelaskan semuanya.
Okay, Mom, be right down. I've gotta get Buzz.
Aku segera turun, ibu. Aku mau ambil Buzz.
Retreat!
Mundur!
Mom, do you know where Buzz is?
Ibu tahu Buzz ada dimana?
No, I haven't seen him.
Aku tak melihatnya.
- Andy, I'm heading out the door! - But, Mom, I can't find him!
Andy, ibu sudah di luar pintu.! Tapi, ibu, aku tak melihatnya.
Honey, just grab some other toy. Now, come on!
Ambil saja mainan lain. Ayo, cepat.
Oh, okay.
Baiklah.
I couldn't find my Buzz. I know I left him right there.
Aku tak bisa menemukan Buzz. Aku taruh dia di situ.
Honey, I'm sure he's around. You'll find him.
Sayang, Ibu yakin Buzz ada. Kau pasti akan menemukannya.
It's too short! We need more monkeys!
Terlalu pendek. Kita butuh kera lagi.
There aren't any more! That's the whole barrel!
Sudah tak ada lagi. Itu sudah satu kotak!
Buzz, the monkeys aren't working!
Buzz, kera ini tak bisa!
We're formulating another plan! Stay calm!
Kami menyusun rencana lain. Tenang.
Oh, where could he be?
Dia ada dimana?
- Can I help pump the gas? - Sure! I'll even let you drive.
Aku boleh bantu isi bensin? Tentu. Kau juga boleh mengemudi.
- Yeah? - Yeah, when you're 16.
Ya?Ya, kalau usiamu sudah 16 tahun.
Funny, Mom.
Lucu sekali, ibu.
Great. How am I gonna convince those guys it was an accident?
Bagus. Bagaimana caranya aku meyakinkan mereka itu kecelakaan?
Buzz!
Buzz!
Buzz! Ha! You're alive!
Buzz! Ha! Kau masih hidup!
This is great! Oh, I'm saved! I'm saved.
Ini bagus. Oh, aku selamat. Aku selamat!
Andy'll find you here, he'll take us back to the room
Andy akan menemukanmu, ia akan bawa kita kembali ke kamarnya...
and then you can tell everyone that this was all just a big mistake.
dan kau bisa katakan pada semuanya bahwa ini kecelakaan.
Huh? Right? Buddy?
Benar, bukan, sobat?
I just want you to know that even though you tried to terminate me,
Aku hanya ingin kau tahu, meski kau berusaha membunuhku...
revenge is not an idea we promote on my planet.
balas dendam itu tak ada di planetku.
- Oh. Well, that's good. - But we're not on my planet, are we?
Oh, itu bagus.'Tapi kita tidak di planetku, bukan?
No.
Tidak.
Okay, come on!
Baiklah, ayo.
You want a piece of me?
Kau ingin berkelahi?
Buzz, Buzz, Buzz Lightyear to the rescue.
Buzz, Buzz, Buzz Lightyear menyelamatkan.
- Next stop. - Pizza Planet! Yeah!
Perhentian yang berikut.! Pizza Planet! Ya!
Wh... Doesn't he realize that I'm not there?
Dia tahu aku tak ada di mobil?
I'm lost!
Aku tersesat.
Oh, I'm a lost toy!
Oh, aku adalah mainan yang tersesat!
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
Catatan misi Buzz Lightyear.
The local sheriff and l seem to be at a huge refueling station of some sort.
Aku dan Sheriff berada di tempat pengisian bahan bakar yang besar.
You!
Kau!
- According to my navi-computer, the... - Shut up!
Menurut komputer navigasi...! Diam!
- Just shut up, you idiot! - Sheriff, this is no time to panic.
Diam, bodoh! Sheriff, ini bukan saatnya panik.
This is the perfect time to panic. I'm lost. Andy is gone.
Ini saat yang tepat untuk panik. Aku tersesat, Andy pergi.
They're gonna move from their house in two days, and it's all your fault!
Dua hari lagi mereka pindah dan ini semua salahmu!
My... My fault? If you hadn't pushed me out of the window in the first place...
Salahku? Kaulah yang mendorong aku dari jendela.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, ya?
Well, if you hadn't shown up in your stupid little cardboard spaceship
Kaulah yang muncul dengan pesawat karton konyolmu...
and taken away everything that was important to me...
dan merampas sesuatu yang penting bagiku.
Don't talk to me about importance!
Jangan bicara kepentingan padaku.
Because of you the security of this entire universe is in jeopardy!
Karena ulahmu keamanan seluruh alam semesta dalam bahaya!
What? What are you talkin’ about?
Apa? Kau membicarakan apa?
Right now, poised at the edge of the galaxy, Emperor Zurg
Sekarang, bersiap di tepi galaksi, Kaisar Zurg...
has been secretly building a weapon
membuat senjata rahasia...
with the destructive capacity to annihilate an entire planet!
yang bisa menghancurkan seluruh planet.
l alone have information that reveals this weapon's only weakness.
Hanya aku yang tahu kelemahan senjata itu.
And you, my friend, are responsible
Dan kau, teman, bertanggung jawab...
for delaying my rendezvous with Star Command!
akan tertundanya pertemuanku dengan Komando Bintang.
You... are... a... toy!
Kau ini mainan!
You aren't the real Buzz Lightyear! You're a...
Kau bukan Buzz Lightyear yang sesungguhnya.
You're an action figure! You are a child's plaything!
Kau hanya boneka! Kau mainan anak-anak!
You are a sad, strange little man, and you have my pity.
Kau manusia kecil yang aneh dan menyedihkan. Aku merasa iba.
Farewell.
Selamat tinggal.
Oh, yeah? Well, good riddance, ya loony!
Oh, ya? Pergilah, orang gila.
"Rendezvous with Star Command."
“Bertemu dengan Komando Bintang.”
- Hey, gas dude! - You talkin’ to me?
Hey, bensin!)Kau bicara padaku?
- Yeah, man. Can you help me? - Pizza Planet? Andy!
Ya, kau bisa menolongku?! Pizza Planet? Andy!
Do you know where Cutting Boulevard is?
Kau tahu dimana jalan memotong?
Oh, no!
Oh, tidak!
I can't show my face in that room without Buzz.
Aku tak bisa muncul di ruangan itu tanpa Buzz.
- Buzz! Buzz, come back! - Go away!
Buzz! Buzz, kembali!!Enyahlah!
No! Buzz, you gotta come back! I...
Tidak, Buzz, kau harus kembali.
I found a spaceship!
Aku menemukan pesawat ruang angkasa!
It's a spaceship, Buzz!
Pesawat ruang angkasa, Buzz!
Come on, man, hurry up! Like, the pizzas are getting cold here!
Ayo. Cepat. Pizzanya nanti dingin.
- Cutting Boulevard, huh? - Yeah, yeah. Which way?
Jalan memotong?! Ya, ya. Kemana?
Now, you're sure this space freighter will return to its port of origin
Kau yakin pesawat angkut itu kembali ke tempat asalnya...
once it jettisons its food supply?
setelah mengirimkan pasokan makanan?
And when we get there, we'll be able to find a way to transport you home.
Jika kita sampai, kita bisa mencari jalan untuk membawa kau kembali.
- Well, then, let's climb aboard. - No, no, no, wait, Buzz! Buzz!
Jika begitu, naiklah! Tidak, tunggu, Buzz! Buzz!
Let's get in the back. No one will see us there.
Di belakang, agar tak ada yang melihat kita.
Negative. There are no restraining harnesses in the cargo area.
Tidak. Di ruang muatan tak ada sabuk pengaman.
- We'll be much safer in the cockpit. - Yeah, bu...
Di ruang kemudi lebih aman.! Ya, tapi...
Buzz! Buzz!
Buzz! Buzz!
That's two lefts and a right, huh?
Dua kiri lalu kanan, bukan?
- Thanks for the directions, okay? - Yeah. And remember, kid...
Terima kasih untuk petunjuknya.! Ya, dan ingat, nak...
Buzz!
Buzz!
It's safer in the cockpit than the cargo bay. What an idiot.
Lebih aman di ruang kemudi daripada di ruang barang. Bodoh sekali.
Next shuttle lift-off is scheduled for
Peluncuran ulang alik dijadwalkan berangkat...
T-minus 30 minutes and counting.
30 menit lagi.
You are clear to enter.
Silahkan masuk.
Welcome to Pizza Planet.
Selamat datang di Pizza Planet.
The white zone is for immediate pizza...
Daerah putih hanya untuk pengambilan pizza.
Sheriff!
Sheriff!
There you are.
Rupanya kau disini.
Now, the entrance is heavily guarded. We need a way to get inside.
Pintu dijaga ketat. Kita harus cari cara untuk masuk.
Great idea, Woody.
Ide bagus, Woody.
I like your thinkin’.
Aku suka pemikiranmu.
You are clear to enter. Welcome to Pizza Planet.
Silakan masuk. Selamat datang di Pizza Planet.
Now!
Sekarang!
Quickly, Sheriff! The air lock is closing.
Cepat, Sheriff! Pintu akan menutup.
Jones, party of five, your shuttle is now boarding...
Jones, 5 orang, siap naik ke taksi anda...
Hey, Mom, can we have some tokens?
Hey, ibu, bolehkah kami minta uang?
Watch where you're going!
Hati-hati kalau berjalan.
Sorry.
Maaf.
Nine, eight, seven, six,
9, 8, 7, 6...
five, four, three,
PENGONTROL MISI 5, 4 3, 2, 1.
What a spaceport! Good work, Woody.
Bandar angkasa luar yang hebat. Bagus, Woody.
Mom, can I play Black Hole? Please, please, please?
Aku boleh main Black Hole? Boleh, boleh?
- Andy! - Now, we need to find a ship
Andy!Kita butuh pesawat...
- that's headed for Sector 12. - Wait a minute. No, Buzz! This way.
yang menuju ke Sektor 12.! Tunggu. Jangan, Buzz. Lewat sini.
- There's a special ship. I just saw it. - You mean it has hyperdrive?
Aku melihat pesawat istimewa.! Yang memakai hyperdrive?
Hyperactive hyperdrive.
Hyperdrive yang hiperaktif.
And Astro... turf!
Dan rumput astro.
- Where is it? I don't see the... - Come on. That's it.
Dimana? Aku tidak lihat...! Ayo. Itu dia.
Spaceship!
Pesawat luar angkasa.
All right, Buzz, get ready. And...
Bersiaplah, Buzz.
- And the universe explodes! - Okay, Buzz, when I say go,
alam semesta meledak!! Buzz, kalau aku bilang mulai...
we're gonna jump in the basket. Buzz!
kita akan loncat ke keranjang. Buzz!
- No! - Mom, if I eat all my pizza,
Tidak.fJika pizza habis...
can Il have some alien slime?
boleh aku dapat lendir angkasa?
This cannot be happening to me.
Ini tak mungkin terjadi padaku.
- A stranger. - From the outside.
Orang asing.'Dari luar.
Greetings. ! am Buzz Lightyear.
Salam. Aku Buzz Lightyear.
Il come in peace.
Aku datang dan bermaksud baik.
Before your space journey, re-energize yourself
Sebelum kau ke angkasa, tambahkan tenagamu...
with a slice of pepperoni, now boarding at counter three.
dengan sepotong pepperoni, tersedia di meja 3.
This is an intergalactic emergency.
Ini situasi darurat antar galaksi.
I need to commandeer your vessel to Sector 12.
Aku harus mengendalikan pesawatmu ke Sektor 12.
Who's in charge here?
Siapa yang memimpin di sini?
The claw!
Si cakar!
The claw is our master.
Cakar itu majikan kami.
The claw chooses who will go and who will stay.
la menentukan siapa yang tinggal dan siapa yang pergi.
- This is ludicrous. - Hey, bozo, you got a brain in there?
Ini konyol.JKalian punya otak?
Take that!
Terima itu!
Oh, no! Sid!
Oh, tidak! Sid!
Get down!
Tiarap!
What's gotten into you? I was...
Ada apa denganmu?
You are the one that decided to climb into this...
Kau yang masuk ke dalam...
The claw, it moves.
Cakar itu bergerak.
l have been chosen!
Aku terpilih.
Farewell, my friends. I go on to a better place.
Selamat tinggal, teman. Aku pergi ke tempat yang lebih baik.
Gotcha!
Dapat!
A Buzz Lightyear? No way!
Buzz Lightyear? Tak mungkin!
Yes!
Hebat!
Buzz! No!
Buzz! Tidak!
Hey!
Hei!
He has been chosen!
Dia sudah terpilih.
- He must go. - Hey!
Dia harus pergi.'Hei!
- What are you doing? - Do not fight the claw.
Apa yang kau lakukan?) Jangan membantah si cakar.
Stop it! Stop it, you zealots!
Hentikanlah, kau fanatik!
All right! Double prizes!
Bagus! Dua hadiah!
Let's go home and... play.
Ayo pulang dan main.
Sheriff, l can see your dwelling from here.
Sheriff, aku lihat rumahmu.
- You're almost home. - Nirvana is coming.
Kau sudah dekat.! Nirwana semakin dekat.
- The mystic portal awaits. - Will you be quiet?
Pintu mistik menunggu.! Bisakah kau diam?
You guys don't get it, do you?
Kalian tidak mengerti?
Once we go into Sid's house, we won't be coming out.
Kalau masuk ke rumah Sid, kita takkan bisa keluar.
Whoa, Scud! Hey, boy!
Scud! Hei, nak!
Sit! Good boy.
Duduk! Anak baik.
- Hey, I got something for you, boy. - Freeze!
Aku punya sesuatu untukmu.! Jangan bergerak!
Ready, set, now!
Siap, awas, sekarang!
Hannah! Hey, Hannah!
Hannah! Hei, Hannah!
- What? - Did I get my package in the mail?
Apa?!Paketku sudah tiba?
- [don't know. - What do you mean you don't know?
Aku tak tahu.! Apa maksudmu kau tidak tahu?
I don't know!
Aku tak tahu.
- Oh, no, Hannah! Look, Janie! - What? Hey!
Oh, tidak, Hannah! Lihat, Janie!J Apa? Hei!
- She's sick! - No, she's not!
Dia sakit.'Tidak.
I'll have to perform one of my operations.
Aku harus melakukan operasi.
- No! - No, not Sid's room. Not there.
Tidak.fJangan ke kamar Sid.
Hey, give her back!
Hei, kembalikan dia!
Sid! Sid!
Sid! Sid!
Oh, no, we have a sick patient here, nurse.
Oh, tidak, ada pasien yang sakit, suster.
Prepare the OR, stat!
Siapkan ruang operasi, segera!
Patient is... prepped.
Pasien sudah dipersiapkan.
No one's ever attempted a double bypass brain transplant before.
Tak pernah ada yang mencoba pencangkokan otak ganda.
Now for the tricky part. Pliers!
Sekarang bagian yang sulit. Tang.
I don't believe that man's ever been to medical school.
Kurasa ia tak pernah kuliah di sekolah kedokteran.
Doctor, you've done it!
Dokter, kau berhasil!
Hannah!
Hannah!
Janie's all better now.
Janie kini sudah baik.
- Mom! Mom! - She's lying!
Ibu! Ibu!Dia bohong!
Whatever she says, it's not true!
Apapun yang ia katakan itu tidak benar.
We are gonna die. I'm outta here!
Kita akan mati. Aku pergi dari sini.
Locked.
Terkunci.
There's gotta be another way outta here.
Pasti ada jalan keluar lain.
Buzz? Was that you?
Buzz? Kaukah itu?
Hey, hi there, little fella.
Hei, teman cilik.
Come out here. Do you know a way outta here?
Kemarilah. Kau tahu jalan keluar dari sini?
Buzz!
Buzz!
They're cannibals.
Mereka kanibal.
Mayday, mayday.
Tolong, tolong.
Come in, Star Command. Send reinforcements.
Masuk, Komando Bintang. Kirim bantuan.
Star Command, do you copy?
Komando Bintang, bisa dengar?
I've set my laser from stun to kill.
Aku memasang laserku untuk mematikan.
Great. Great. Yeah, and if anyone attacks us, we can blink 'em to death.
Bagus. Ya, kalau ada yang menyerang, kita bisa bunuh mereka dengan kedipan.
Hey, you guys, I think I found him!
Hei, kurasa aku menemukannya.
Buzz, is that you?
Buzz, kaukah itu?
Whiskers, will you get outta here!
Whiskers, keluar dari sini!
You're interfering with the search and rescue!
Kau mengganggu pencarian dan penyelamatan.
Look, they're home.
Lihat, mereka sudah pulang.
Mom, have you seen Woody?
Ibu lihat Woody?
- Where was the last place you left him? - Right here in the van.
Kapan terakhir kau melihatnya?! Di mobil.
Oh, I'm sure he's there. You're just not looking hard enough.
Oh, aku yakin dia ada. Cari lagi.
He's not here, Mom. Woody's gone.
Tidak ada, ibu. Woody hilang.
Woody's gone?
Woody hilang?
Yeah, boy, the weasel ran away.
Ya, penjahat itu lari.
Huh? Huh? I told you he was guilty.
Apa aku bilang? Dia bersalah.
Who would've thought he was capable of such atrocities?
Siapa yang mengira ia bisa melakukan kejahatan seperti itu?
Oh, Slink, I hope he's okay.
Oh, Slink, aku harap dia tidak apa-apa.
Oh, a survivor. Where's the rebel base? Talk!
Ada yang selamat. Mana markas pemberontaknya? Katakan!
I can see your will is strong.
Aku tahu sikapmu teguh.
Well, we have ways of making you talk.
Kami punya cara untuk membuatmu bicara.
Where are your rebel friends now?
Mana teman-teman pemberontakmu sekarang?
Sid, your Pop Tarts are ready!
Sid, Pop Tart-mu sudah siap!
All right!
Sedap!
Are you all right? I'm proud of you, Sheriff.
Kau tak apa-apa? Aku bangga padamu, Sheriff.
A lesser man would've talked under such torture.
Orang lemah sudah bicara jika disiksa begitu.
Il sure hope this isn't permanent.
Semoga bekas luka ini bisa hilang.
The door. It's open! We're free!
Pintu itu terbuka! Kita bebas!
- Woody, we don't know what's out there! - I'll tell you wha...
Woody, kita tak tahu situasinya.! Kukatakan apa...
They're gonna eat us, Buzz! Do something quick!
Mereka akan memakan kita, Buzz! Lakukan sesuatu!
Shield your eyes.
Lindungi matamu.
It's not working. I recharged it before I left. It should be good for...
Tidak berhasil. Aku sudah mengisinya. Seharusnya bisa...
You idiot! You're a toy! Use your karate chop action!
Dasar bodoh! Kau ini mainan! Gunakan gerakan karatemu.
- Get away! - Hey! Hey! How're you doin’ that?
Minggir!Hei! Bagaimana kau lakukan itu?
- Stop that. - Back! Back, you savages! Back!
Hentikan itu.! Mundur! Jahanam, mundur!
- Woody, stop it! - Sorry, guys, but dinner's canceled!
Woody, hentikan!! Maaf, tapi santap malam dibatalkan.
There's no place like home!
Tak ada tempat yang lebih nyaman dari rumah.
Another stunt like that, cowboy, you're gonna get us killed.
Tindakan sembrono seperti itu bisa membunuh kita.
Don't tell me what to do.
Jangan suruh aku.
Yee-haw! Giddyap, pardner!
Ayo! Maju, rekan!
We got to get this wagon train a-movin'!
Kita harus menjalankan rombongan kereta ini.
Split up!
Berpencar!
Calling Buzz Lightyear. Come in, Buzz Lightyear.
Memanggil Buzz Lightyear. Masuk, Buzz Lightyear.
- This is Star Command. - Star Command!
Ini Komando Bintang.
- Buzz Lightyear, do you read me? - Buzz Lightyear responding.
Buzz Lightyear, kau bisa dengar?! Buzz Lightyear menjawab.
Read you loud and clear.
Mendengar jelas sekali.
Buzz Lightyear, planet Earth needs your help.
Buzz Lightyear, planet bumi butuh pertolonganmu.
- On the way! - Buzz Lightyear!
Segera!)Buzz Lightyear!
The world's greatest superhero! Now the world's greatest toy!
Pahlawan dunia terhebat, kini jadi mainan terhebat di dunia.
Buzz has it all! Locking wrist communicator!
Buzz memiliki semuanya! Alat komunikasi di pergelangan tangan.
- Calling Buzz Lightyear! - Karate chop action!
Memanggil Buzz Lightyeary Gerakan karate!
- Wow! - Pulsating laser light!
Wah!Sinar laser.
- Total annihilation! - Multi-phase voice simulator!
Penghancuran totalY Pengubah suara beraneka ragam.
There's a secret mission in uncharted space.
Ada tugas rahasia di angkasa yang belum jelajahi.
And best of aif, high pressure space wings!
Yang terbaik, sayap angkasa tekanan tinggi.
- To infinity and beyond! - Not a flying toy.
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
Get your Buzz Lightyear action figure
Dapatkan Buzz Lightyear...
- and save a galaxy near you! - Buzz Lightyear!
dan selamatkan galaksi didekatmu.' Buzz Lightyear!
Available at aif Al's Toy Barn outlets in the tri-county area.
Tersedia di seluruh toko mainan Al di daerahmu.
Out among the stars I sit
Aku duduk di antara bintang-bintang.
Way beyond the moon
Jauh di balik bulan.
In my silver ship I sailed
Aku berlayar dengan kapal perakku.
Toadream that ended too soon
Menuju impian yang terlalu cepat berakhir.
Now I know exactly
Kini aku tahu...
Who I am and what I'm here for
Siapa aku sebenarnya dan tugasku.
You are a toy! You can't fly!
Kau mainan! Kau tak bisa terbang!
And I will go sailing
Dan aku takkan berlayar...
No more
lagi.
But no, it can't be true
Tapi, itu tidak benar.
! could fly if l wanted to
Aku bisa terbang jika aku ingin.
Like a bird in the sky
Seperti burung di angkasa.
If l believed I could fly
Jika aku percaya aku bisa terbang...
Why, I'd fly
aku akan terbang.
To infinity and beyond!
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
Clearly, I
Sudah jelas, aku...
Will go sailing
takkan berlayar...
No more
lagi.
Mom! Mom, have you seen my Sally doll?
Ibu lihat boneka Sally-ku?
What, dear? What was that?
Kau bilang apa, sayang?
Never mind!
Lupakanlah.
Buzz, the coast is clear. Buzz, where are you?
Buzz, keadaan sudah aman. Buzz, kau dimana?
There's a secret mission in uncharted space. Let's go.
Ada tugas rahasia di ruang angkasa. Ayo berangkat.
Really? That is so interesting.
Benarkah? Itu menarik sekali.
Would you like some tea, Mrs. Nesbitt?
Anda ingin teh, Ny. Nesbitt?
Buzz!
Buzz!
It's so nice you could join us on such late notice.
Senang sekali kau bisa bergabung dengan kami.
- Oh, no! - What a lovely hat, Mrs. Nesbitt.
Oh, tidak!) Topimu bagus, Ny. Nesbitt.
It goes quite well with your head.
Cocok sekali dengan kepalamu.
Hannah! Oh, Hannah!
Hannah! Oh, Hannah!
Mom? Please excuse me, ladies.
Ibu? Permisi, ibu-ibu.
I'll be right back.
Aku akan segera kembali.
What is it, Mom? Mom, where are you?
Ada apa, ibu? Ibu, kau dimana?
Buzz. Hey. Buzz, are you okay?
Buzz. Hei. Buzz, kau tidak apa-apa?
Gone! It's all gone.
Lenyap! Semuanya lenyap.
All of it's gone. Bye-bye. See ya.
Semuanya lenyap. Selamat tinggal. Sampai jumpa.
What happened to you?
Apa yang terjadi padamu?
One minute you're defending the whole galaxy.
Satu saat kau membela seluruh galaksi...
And suddenly you find yourself suckin’ down Darjeeling with
dan tiba-tiba kau minum teh Darjeeling dengan...
Marie Antoinette and her little sister.
Marie Antoinette dan adiknya.
I think you've had enough tea for today.
Kau sudah cukup banyak minum teh.
Let's get you outta here, Buzz.
Ayo kita pergi dari sini, Buzz.
Don't you get it? You see the hat?
Kau tak mengerti? Kau lihat topi ini?
- lam Mrs. Nesbitt! - Snap out of it, Buzz!
Aku Ny. Nesbitt!!Sadarlah, Buzz!
I'm sorry. I... You're right.
Maaf. Kau benar.
lam just a little depressed. That's all.
Aku hanya sedikit tertekan, itu saja.
I can get through this.
Aku bisa mengatasi kesulitan ini.
Oh, I'm a sham!
Aku palsu!
- Look at me. - Quiet, Buzz.
Lihat aku.lDiam, Buzz.
I can't even fly out of a window.
Aku tak bisa terbang keluar jendela.
The hat looked good? Tell me the hat looked good.
Topinya bagus? Katakan bahwa topinya bagus.
Buzz, you're a genius!
Buzz, kau jenius!
Come on, come on. This way.
Ayo, ayo. Lewat sini.
Years of academy, training, wasted!
Bertahun-tahun pendidikan di akademi, sia-sia.
B-3.
B-3.
Miss! G-6.
Luput! G-6.
You sunk it. Are you peeking?
Kau menenggelamkannya. Kau mengintip?
Oh, quit your whinin' and pay up. No, no, not the ear.
Jangan merengek saja dan bayar. Bukan telinga.
- Give me the nose. Come on. - How about three out of five?
Berikan hidungmu.! Menang 3 kali dari 5 kali main?
Hey, guys! Guys! Hey!
Hei, rekan-rekan.
- Son of a building block. It's Woody. - He's in the psycho's bedroom.
Astaga, itu Woody.! la di kamar anak gila itu!
- Hi! - Everyone! It's Woody!
Hai!!Semua, itu Woody!
- Woody? - You're kidding!
Woody?)Kau bercanda!
- We're gonna get outta here, Buzz.
Woody?Kita akan keluar dari sini, Buzz.
Buzz?
Buzz?
- Hey, look! - Woody!
Hei, lihat!oody!
Oh, boy, am I glad to see you guys.
Aku senang melihat kalian.
- [knew you'd come back, Woody. - What are you doin’ over there?
Aku tahu kau akan kembali, Woody.! Kau sedang apa?
It's a long story, Bo. I'll explain later.
Ceritanya panjang, Bo. Aku akan cerita nanti.
Here! Catch this!
Tangkap ini.
- Whoa! I've got it, Woody. - He got it, Woody.
Aku sudah memegangnya.! la sudah memegangnya!
Good goin’, Slink. Now just, just tie it on to somethin’.
Bagus, Slink. Sekarang ikatkan ke sesuatu.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. I got a better idea. How ‘bout we don't?
Tunggu. Aku punya ide lebih baik. Bagaimana jika tidak?
- Hey! - Potato Head.
Hei!Potato Head.
Did you all take stupid pills this morning?
Kalian minum pil bodoh pagi ini?
Have you forgotten what he did to Buzz?
Kalian sudah lupa perlakuannya pada Buzz?
And now you wanna let him back over here?
Kalian ingin membiarkan dia kembali?
No! No, no, no, no, no! You got it... You got it all wrong, Potato Head.
Tidak, tidak, tidak. Kau salah sangka, Potato Head.
Buzz is fine. Buzz is right here. He's with me!
Buzz baik-baik saja. la bersamaku di sini.
- You are a liar! - No, I'm not. Buzz, come over here.
Bohong!Tidak. Buzz, kemarilah.
Tell the nice toys that you're... that you're not dead.
Katakan pada mereka kau tidak mati.
Buzz, will you get up here and give me a hand?
Buzz, bisakah kau kemari dan bantu aku?
That's very funny, Buzz.
Itu lucu sekali, Buzz.
- This is serious! - Hey, Woody! Where'd ya go?
Ini serius.! Hei, Woody! Kau kemana?
He's lying. Buzz ain't there.
Dia bohong. Buzz tidak ada.
Oh! Hi, Buzz!
Oh! Hai, Buzz!
Why don't you say hello to the guys over there?
Buzz, ucapkan salam pada teman-teman di sana.
Hiya, fellas! To infinity and beyond!
Hai, kawan! Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
Hey, look! It's Buzz!
Lihat! Itu Buzz!
Hey, Buzz, let's show the guys our new secret best friends handshake.
Buzz, perlihatkan jabat tangan rahasia baru kita.
Give me five, man!
Beri aku salam!
Something's screwy here.
Ada yang mencurigakan.
So you see we're friends now, guys. Aren't we, Buzz?
Kita kini berteman. Benar, Buzz?
You bet. Give me a hug.
Pasti. Peluk aku.
Boy, I love you too.
Aku sayang padamu juga.
See? It is Buzz.
Lihat. Itu Buzz.
- Now give back the lights, Potato Head. - Wait just a minute.
Kembalikan lampunya, Potato Head.! Tunggu sebentar.
- What are you tryin’ to pull? - Nothing!
Tipuan apa lagi yang akan kau lakukan?Tidak ada.
- Oh, that is disgusting. - Murderer!
Oh, itu menjijikkan.'Pembunuh!
- No! No, no, no, no, no! - You murdering dog!
Tidak, tidak, tidak!J Kau anjing pembunuh!
- It's not what you think. I swear! - Save it for the jury.
Ini bukan yang kalian kira.! Katakan saja pada juri.
l hope Sid pulls your voice box out, ya creep.
Aku harap Sid merusak kotak suaramu.
No, no! No, no! Don't leave! Don't leave!
Tidak, tidak! Jangan pergi.
Ya gotta help us, please! You don't know what it's like over here!
Mohon, tolong aku. Kalian tak tahu bagaimana keadaan.
Come on. Let's get outta here.
Ayo, kita pergi.
Go back to your lives, citizens. Show's over.
Ayo, bubar. Pertunjukan selesai.
Come back! Slink!
Kembali! Slink!
Slink! Please! Please! Listen to me!
Slink! Aku mohon! Mohon! Dengarkan aku!
No! No! Come back!
Tidak! Kembali!
Slinky!
Slinky!
Buzz! Go away!
Buzz! Pergilah!
You disgusting freaks!
Kau menjijikkan!
All right, back! Back, you cannibals!
Mundur! Mundur, kau kanibal!
He is still alive, and you're not gonna get him, you monsters!
la masih hidup dan kalian takkan bisa memakannya, monster!
What are you doin'?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Hey. Hey, they fixed you.
Hei, mereka membetulkanmu.
But they're cannibals.
Tapi mereka kanibal.
We saw them eat those other toys.
Kita lihat mereka memakan mainan lainnya.
Sorry. I thought that you were gonna...
Maaf. Kukira kalian akan...
You know, you know, eat my friend.
memakan temanku.
Hey, no, no, wait, hey!
Hei, jangan, tunggu!
- What's wrong? - Sid?
Ada masalah apa?Sid?
Not now, Mom! I'm busy!
Tunggu, ibu! Aku sibuk.
- Sid! Buzz, come on! - You left that door open.
Sid! Buzz, ayo! Kau membiarkan pintu itu terbuka.
Get up! Use your legs! Fine! Let Sid trash you! But don't blame me!
Bangun! Pakai kakimu! Biarkan Sid merusaknya, tapi jangan salahkan aku!
It came! It finally came!
Paketnya akhirnya datang!
"The Big One."
“Yang Besar.”
"Extremely dangerous.
“Sangat berbahaya.
Keep out of reach of children."
Jauhkan dari jangkauan anak-anak.”
Cool! What am I gonna blow?
Hebat! Aku akan meledakkan apa?
Man. Hey, where's that wimpy cowboy doll?
Mana boneka koboi pengecut itu?
Yes. I've always wanted to put a spaceman into orbit.
Aku sudah lama ingin mengorbitkan astronot.
Now. Yes.
Sekarang. Ya.
Oh, no!
Oh, tidak!
Sid Phillips reporting.
Sid Phillips melaporkan.
Launch of the shuttle has been delayed
Peluncuran pesawat ulang alik ditunda...
due to adverse weather conditions at the launch site.
karena kondisi cuaca di lokasi peluncuran.
Tomorrow's forecast: sunny.
Prakiraan cuaca besok: cerah.
Sweet dreams.
Mimpi indah.
l looked everywhere, honey, but all I could find was your hat.
Ibu mencari ke mana-mana tapi hanya menemukan topimu.
But what if we leave them behind?
Bagaimana jika mereka sampai tertinggal?
Oh, don't worry, honey.
Oh, jangan khawatir, sayang.
I'm sure we'll find Woody and Buzz before we leave tomorrow.
Kita akan menemukan Woody dan Buzz sebelum berangkat besok.
I need air!
Aku butuh udara!
Will you quit movin' around?
Bisakah jangan bergerak?
I'm sorry. It's just that I get... I get so nervous before I travel.
Maaf. Aku tegang jika mau bepergian.
How did I get stuck with you as a moving buddy?
Mengapa aku mendapatkanmu sebagai teman pindah?
Everyone else was picked.
Semuanya sudah punya teman.
Oh, Woody.
Oh, Woody.
If only you could see how much Andy misses you.
Andai saja kau tahu betapa Andy amat merindukanmu.
Hey, Buzz!
Hei, Buzz!
Hey. Get over here and see if you can get this toolbox off me.
Coba kau dorong kotak peralatan ini.
Oh, come on, Buzz, l...
Oh, ayolah, Buzz, aku...
Buzz, I can't do this without you. I need your help.
Buzz, aku tak bisa kabur tanpa bantuanmu. Aku butuh bantuanmu.
I can't help. I can't help anyone.
Aku tak bisa membantu. Aku tak bisa membantu siapapun.
Why, sure you can, Buzz. You can get me outta here.
Kau bisa, Buzz. Kau keluarkan aku dari sini.
Then I'll get that rocket off you, and we'll make a break for Andy's house.
Aku lepaskan roket dari badanmu dan kita lari ke rumah Andy.
Andy's house, Sid's house. What's the difference?
Rumah Andy, rumah Sid. Apa bedanya?
Oh, Buzz. You've had a big fall. You must not be thinking clearly.
Buzz, kau jatuh dari tempat tinggi. Kau tak berpikir jernih.
No, Woody. For the first time lam thinking clearly.
Tidak, Woody. Untuk pertama kalinya aku berpikir jernih.
You were right all along. I'm not a Space Ranger.
Kau benar. Aku bukan Penjaga Angkasa.
I'm just a toy, a stupid, little, insignificant toy.
Aku hanya mainan kecil bodoh yang tak berguna.
Whoa, hey, wait a minute.
Hei, tunggu.
- Yeah, right. - No, it is.
Ya, benar.!Memang begitu.
Look, over in that house is a kid who thinks you are the greatest.
Di seberang itu ada anak yang menganggap kau paling hebat.
And it's not because you're a Space Ranger, pal.
Bukan karena kau Penjaga Angkasa, teman.
It's because you're a toy. You are his toy.
Karena kau mainan. Kau mainannya.
But why would Andy want me?
Tapi mengapa Andy menginginkanku?
Why would Andy want you? Look at you! You're a Buzz Lightyear.
Mengapa Andy menginginkanmu? Lihat dirimu. Kau Buzz Lightyear.
Any other toy would give up his moving parts just to be you.
Mainan mana saja mau memberikan bagiannya untuk jadi dirimu.
You've got wings. You glow in the dark. You talk!
Kau punya sayap. Kau menyala di tempat gelap. Kau bisa bicara.
Your helmet does that, that, that whoosh thing.
Helmmu bisa terbuka.
You are a cool toy.
Kau mainan yang hebat.
As a matter of fact, you're too cool.
Sebenarnya, kau terlalu hebat.
I mean, I mean, what chance does a toy like me have
Maksudku, bagaimana aku bisa...
against a Buzz Lightyear action figure?
mengalahkan Buzz Lightyear?
All can do is...
Aku hanya bisa mengatakan...
There's a snake in my boots.
ada ular di sepatuku.
Why would Andy ever want to play with me
Untuk apa Andy ingin bermain denganku...
when he's got you?
kalau ia mempunyaimu?
I'm the one that should be strapped to that rocket.
Akulah yang harusnya dipasangi roket.
Listen, Buzz, forget about me.
Dengar, Buzz, lupakan aku.
You should get outta here while you can.
Pergilah dari sini selagi kau bisa.
Buzz? What are you doin'? I thought you were...
Buzz, apa yang kau lakukan? Kukira kau...
Come on, sheriff. There's a kid over in that house who needs us.
Ayo, Sheriff. Anak di seberang itu membutuhkan kita.
Now let's get you out of this thing.
Aku akan mengeluarkanmu dari kotak ini.
Yes, sir!
Ya, pak!
Come on, Buzz. We can do it.
Ayo, Buzz. Kita bisa.
Woody, it's the moving van.
Woody, itu mobil pindahan.
We gotta get outta here now.
Kita harus keluar dari sini sekarang.
Come on, Buzz.
Ayo, Buzz.
All right.
Baiklah.
- Hey, I'm out! - Almost there.
Hei, aku keluar.!Hampir.
I want to ride the pony.
Aku ingin naik kuda.
Woody? Woody? Are you all right?
Woody? Woody? Kalian baik-baik saja?
I'm fine. I'm okay.
Aku baik-baik saja.
Oh, yeah! Time for lift-off!
Oh, ya! Saat untuk meluncur.
To infinity and beyond!
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
Back, back.
Mundur, mundur.
Down, down!
Turun, turun.
Guys!
Teman-teman!
No, no, no, no! Wait! Wait. Listen, please.
Tidak! Tunggu! Mohon dengarkan.
There's a good toy down there, and he's gonna be blown to bits in a few minutes.
Ada mainan baik dan ia akan hancur berkeping-keping.
All because of me. We gotta save him.
Itu semua karena aku. Kita harus menyelamatkannya.
And... But I need your help.
Tapi aku butuh bantuan kalian.
Please. He's my friend.
Aku mohon. Ia temanku.
And he's the only one I've got.
la satu-satunya temanku.
Thank you. Okay, I think 1 know what to do.
Terima kasih. Kukira aku tahu apa yang harus kulakukan.
We're gonna have to break a few rules.
Kita harus melanggar beberapa aturan...
But if it works, it'll help everybody.
tapi jika itu berhasil, itu akan membantu semuanya.
Houston to Mission Control. Come in, Control.
Houston ke Kendali Misi. Jawablah.
Launch pad is being constructed.
Tempat peluncuran sedang dibangun.
All right, listen up.
Baiklah, dengarkan.
I need Pump Boy here, Ducky here.
Aku minta Pump Boy di sini, Ducky di sini.
Legs, you're with Ducky.
Legs, kau dengan Ducky.
RollerBob and I don't move ‘til we get the signal. Clear?
Aku dan Roller Bob menunggu tandanya. Paham?
Okay. Let's move!
Ayo, kita laksanakan!
Wind the frog.
Putar kataknya.
Wait for the signal.
Tunggu tandanya.
Go!
Laksanakan!
All right, let's go!
Ayo, mulai!
I'll get it!
Akan aku buka.
Now!
Sekarang!
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Sebentar. Sebentar.
Scud!
Scud!
Stupid dog.
Anjing bodoh.
Lean back!
Condong ke belakang.
Mission Control, is the launch pad construction complete?
Kendali Misi, tempat peluncuran sudah selesai?
Roger. Rocket is now secured to guide wire.
Siap. Roket sudah terpasang ke kabel pemandu.
We are currently obtaining the ignition sticks.
Kami mengambil tongkat pembakar.
Countdown will commence momentarily.
Siap untuk hitungan mundur.
- Stand by. - Let's go.
Siap.!Ayo.
Hey, Ma! Where are the matches? Oh, wait. Here they are. Never mind.
Ibu, korek apinya dimana? Oh, tunggu. Ini dia. Lupakanlah.
Woody! Great! Help me outta this thing.
Woody! Bagus! Lepaskan aku dari roket ini.
- What? - It's okay. Everything's under control.
Apa?!Tak apa-apa. Semuanya sudah terkendali.
Woody, what are you doing?
Woody, apa yang kau lakukan?
Houston. All systems are go. Requesting permission to launch...
Houston, semua sistem berfungsi. Minta ijin untuk peluncuran.
Hey? How'd you get out here?
Bagaimana kau bisa ada di sini?
Oh, well. You and I can have a cookout later.
Kau dan aku bisa melakukan bakar-bakaran nanti.
Houston, do we have permission to launch?
Houston, sudah ada izin untuk peluncuran?
Roger. Permission granted.
Benar. Izin diberikan.
You are confirmed at "T" minus ten seconds.
Peluncuran dalam 10 detik...
And counting. Ten, nine,
dan menghitung. 10, 9...
eight, seven, six,
8, 7,6...
five, four, three, two,
5,4,3, 2...
- one! - Reach for the sky!
Angkat tangan!
This town ain't big enough for the two of us.
Kota ini tidak cukup besar untuk kita berdua.
What?
Apa?
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
Ada yang meracuni mata air.
- It's busted. - Who are you callin’ busted, buster?
Rusak.! Siapa bilang rusak?
That's right
Benar.
I'm talking to you, Sid Phillips.
Aku bicara padamu, Sid Phillips.
We don't like bein' blown up, Sid,
Kami tak suka diledakkan, Sid...
or smashed or ripped apart.
atau dihancurkan atau dibongkar.
- "We"? - That's right! Your toys!
“Kami”?! Benar. Mainanmu!
Mama!
Ibu!
Mama! Mama!
Ibu! Ibu!
From now on, you must take good care of your toys!
Mulai sekarang, kau harus merawat mainanmu.
Because if you don't, we'll find out, Sid.
Karena jika tidak, kami akan mencarimu, Sid.
We toys can see everything.
Kami, mainan, bisa melihat semuanya.
So play nice.
Jadi bermainlah dengan baik.
We did it! We did it! Yes!
Kita berhasil! Kita berhasil!
The toys! The toys are alive!
Mainan! Mainan itu hidup!
Nice toy.
Mainan yang baik.
What's wrong, Sid?
Ada apa, Sid?
Don't you want to play with Sally?
Kau tak mau main dengan Sally?
Nice work, fellows. Good job.
Pekerjaan yang bagus.
Comin’ out of the ground, what a touch. That was a stroke of genius.
Muncul dari tanah, hebat. Itu tindakan jenius.
Woody.
Woody.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Everybody say, "Bye, house!”
Semua katakan, “Selamat tinggal rumah.”
- Woody! The van! - Bye, house.
Woody! Mobilnya!) Selamat tinggal, rumah.
We gotta run! Thanks, guys!
Kita harus cepat. Terima kasih.
Quick!
Cepat!
Just go. I'll catch up.
Pergilah. Aku akan menyusul.
Come on!
Ayo!
You can do it, Woody!
Kau bisa, Woody!
I got it!
Aku dapat!
I made it.
Aku berhasil.
Get away, you stupid dog! Down!
Pergi, anjing bodoh! Diam!
- Down! - Hold on, Woody!
Diam!Tahan, Woody!
I can't do it.
Aku tidak bisa!
Take care of Andy for me!
Tolong jaga Andy untukku!
No!
Tidak!
Buzz!
Buzz!
Are we there already?
Kita sudah sampai?
- Woody? - How did you...?
Woody?Bagaimana...?
- How'd he get here? - Where have you...?
Kau dari mana?)Dari mana kau...?
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
- What's goin' on? - What's he takin'?
Ada apa?!la mencari apa?
There you are!
Kau rupanya disini!
Hey. What's he doing?
Hei. Apa yang ia lakukan?
He's at it again!
la melakukannya lagi!
- Get him! - Come on!
Serang dia!!Ayo!
No, no!
Jangan!
No, no, no, no! Wait! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Jangan! Tunggu! Tunggu!
Pig pile!
Babi jatuh!
- Get outta that car! - Move it!
Keluar dari mobil!Ayo!
No! Please! You don't understand!
Jangan! Kau tak mengerti!
Buzz is out there. We gotta help him.
Buzz ada di sana. Kalian harus membantunya.
- No! - Toss him overboard!
Tidak!!Lempar dia keluar!
No, no, no! Wait!
Jangan! Tunggu!
- Hooray! - So long, Woody!
Hore!Selamat jalan, Woody!
Oh! Woody!
Oh! Woody!
- Oh! Well, thanks for the ride. - Look out!
Terima kasih tumpangannya.Awas!
Now let's catch up to that truck.
Ayo kita dekati mobil itu.
Guys! Guys! Woody's riding R.C.
Teman-teman, Woody naik R.C.
- What? - And Buzz is with him!
Apa?Dan Buzz bersamanya.
It is Buzz!
Itu Buzz!
Woody was telling the truth.
Woody ternyata benar.
- What have we done? - Great! Now I have guilt.
Apa yang kita lakukan?' Bagus. Kini aku merasa bersalah.
We're almost there!
Kita hampir sampai.
Rocky, the ramp!
Rocky, pintu masuknya!
Look out!
Awas!
Quick! Hold onto my tail!
Cepat! Pegang ekorku!
- Attaboy, Slink! - Oh! Woody!
Bagus, Slink!)Oh! Woody!
Woody! Speed up!
Woody! Cepat!
- Speed up! - The batteries!
Cepat!)Baterainya.
They're runnin’ out!
Baterainya melemah.
Hakuna Matata
Hakuna Matata.
What a wonderful phrase
Kalimat yang indah.
- L can't hold on much longer. - Slink! Hang on!
Aku tidak bisa bertahan lebih lama lagi.'Slink! Tahan!
Great!
Bagus!
Woody! The rocket!
Woody, roketnya!
The match! Yes!
Korek api! Ya!
Thank you, Sid!
Terima kasih, Sid!
No! No, no! No!
Tidak! Tidak!
No! Oh, no!
Tidak! Oh tidak!
No, no, no, no, no,
Tidak, tidak, tidak...
no!
tidak!
No!
Tidak!
- Woody! What are you doing? - Hold still, Buzz!
Woody! Apa yang kau lakukan?) Jangan bergerak, Buzz!
You did it!
Kau berhasil!
Next stop: Andy!
Perhentian yang berikut: Andy!
Wait a minute. I just lit a rocket. Rockets explode!
Tunggu. Aku baru menyalakan roket. Roket meledak!
I should have held on longer.
Aku harusnya bertahan lebih lama.
Look! Look! It's Woody and Buzz comin’ up fast!
Itu Woody dan Buzz, datang dengan cepat!
Woody!
Woody!
Take cover!
Berlindung!
This is the part where we blow up!
Ini bagian dimana kita meledak!
Not today!
Tidak hari ini!
Hey, Buzz! You're flyin’!
Hei, Buzz! Kau terbang!
This isn't flying. This is falling with style.
Ini bukan terbang. Ini jatuh dengan gaya.
To infinity and beyond!
Ke angkasa tanpa batas!
Buzz, we missed the truck.
Buzz, truknya meleset.
We're not aiming for the truck.
Kita bukan mengincar ke truk.
Hey, wow!
Hei, wah!
- What? What is it? - Woody! Buzz!
Ada apa?Woody! Buzz!
Oh, great, you found them. Where were they?
Oh, bagus, kau temukan mereka. Ada dimana?
- Here in the car! - See?
Ada dimobil.'Sudah kukatakan.
Now, what'd I tell you? Right where you left ‘em.
Apa yang ibu bilang? Di tempat kau meninggalkannya.
- Which one can I open first? - Let's let Molly open one.
Mana yang aku buka lebih dahulu? Biar Molly membuka satu.
Frankincense, this is Myrrh.
Kemenyan, ini Dupa.
Hey, heads up, everybody. It's show time.
Perhatikan. Sekarang saatnya pertunjukan.
Whoa! It's time!
Wah! Sudah waktunya.
Oh, Bo.
Oh, Bo.
There's got to be a less painful way to get my attention.
Pasti ada cara yang tak menyakitkan untuk menarik perhatianku.
Merry Christmas, sheriff.
Selamat Natal, Sheriff.
Say, isn't that mistletoe?
Bukankah itu daun bercumbu?
Maybe Andy will get another dinosaur. Like a leaf eater.
Mungkin Andy akan dapat dinosaurus pemakan daun.
That way I could play the dominant predator.
Maka, aku bisa jadi pemangsa dominan.
Quiet, everyone! Quiet!
Tenang, semuanya!
Molly's first present is Mrs. Potato Head.
Hadiah pertama Molly adalah Ny. Potato Head.
Repeat: a Mrs. Potato Head.
Diulang: Ny. Potato Head.
Way to go, Idaho!
Hebat, Idaho!
Gee, I'd better shave.
Sebaiknya aku cukur.
Come in, Frankincense.
Masuk, Kemenyan.
Andy is now opening his first present.
Andy membuka hadiah pertamanya.
- It's... - Buzz. Buzz Lightyear,
Itu. Buzz. Buzz Lightyear...
- 1 can't quite... - you are not worried, are you?
Aku tak bisa... Kau tak khawatir, bukan?
- Me? No, no. - Make out...
Aku? Tidak.! Melihat...
No. No, no, no, no.
Tidak, tidak, tidak.
A large box... It's...
Kotak besar. Itu...
- Are you? - Now, Buzz,
Kau khawatir?Buzz...
what could Andy possibly get that is worse than you?
apa yang mungkin Andy dapat yang lebih buruk darimu?
Oh, what is it? What is it?
Oh, apa itu? Apa itu?
Wow! A puppy!
Wah! Anak anjing!
You've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
When the road looks rough ahead
Saat perjalanan tampak sulit...
And you're miles and miles from your nice, warm bed
dan kau jauh sekali dari ranjangmu yang empuk dan hangat...
You just remember what your old pal said
ingat saja perkataan sahabat lamamu.
Boy, you've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
Yeah, you've got a friend in me
Ya, aku adalah temanmu.
- You got troubles - And I got ‘em too
Kau dapat masalah. Aku dapat masalah juga.
There isn't anything ! wouldn't do for you
Tidak ada yang takkan kulakukan untukmu.
If we stick together we can see it through
Kalau kita tetap bersama, kita dapat mengatasinya.
‘Cause you've got a friend in me
Karena aku adalah temanmu.
You've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.
Some other folks might be a little bit smarter than 1am
Beberapa orang mungkin lebih pandai dari aku.
Bigger and stronger too
Lebih besar dan kuat juga.
Maybe
Mungkin...
But none of them will ever love you the way I do
tapi tidak ada yang menyayangimu seperti aku.
It's me and you, boy
Hanya kau dan aku.
And as the years go by
Bertahun-tahun berlalu...
Our friendship will never die
persahabatan kita takkan pudar.
You're gonna see it's our destiny
Kau akan lihat, itu adalah takdir kita.
You've got a friend in me
Aku adalah temanmu.